Michael Alpert collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
Michael Alpert collection 1956-2008 1974-2008
AFC 2017/048
Alpert, Michael
3,384 items
504 text files: digital; pdf
615 sound cassettes: analog
50 sound discs (mini disc): analog
11 sound cassettes (DAT): digital
4 sound cassettes (microcassette): analog
2,200 sound files: digital; wav, mp3
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Recordings of interviews, conversations, social events, rehearsals, performances, and presentations by klezmer musicians and Yiddish folk singers collected primarily in New York City, Los Angeles, and Eastern Europe.
Provenance
Michael Alpert; Purchase; 2017 and 2021.
Custodial History
In 2014, Michael Alpert sent the recordings to the Center for Traditional Music and Dance (CTMD) where Clara Byom digitized the sound recordings and cassette liners between 2014 and 2021.
Accruals
No further accruals are expected.
Related Material
Related materials can be found in the Center for Traditional Music and Dance collection (AFC 2014/044), to which Alpert contributed as a performer.
Access and Restrictions
The Michael Alpert collection is open to research. To request materials, please contact the Folklife Reading Room at https://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/folklife.contact
Certain restrictions to use or copying of materials may apply.
Biographical Note
Michael Alpert is a scholar, linguist, and performer whose work focuses on the expressive culture of Eastern European Jews in the late nineteenth, twentieth, and early twenty-first centuries in Europe and the United States. His former research affiliations include New York City's YIVO Institute for Jewish Research, the Center for Traditional Music and Dance, Oxford University, Columbia University, Yale University, and Indiana University. He was the 2015 recipient of a National Heritage Fellowship from the National Endowment for the Arts. In addition to his scholarly work on klezmer and Yiddish folk music, he is a performer with the ensembles Brave Old World and Kapelye where he performs primarily on violin, percussion, and accordion.
Scope and Content
The Michael Alpert collection includes field recordings of interviews, conversations, social events, rehearsals, and performances of klezmer music and Yiddish folk songs primarily in New York City, Los Angeles, and Eastern Europe. The collection focuses on the expressive culture of Eastern European Jews in the later nineteenth, twentieth, and early twenty-first centuries and documents immigrant generation and U.S. born practitioners from that period. With recordings in both English and Yiddish, the collection thoroughly documents aspects of vernacular culture and history, especially in light of the cataclysmic displacement and dispersion of Eastern European Jews in the twentieth century.
The analog materials that were digitized at CTMD are available as both WAV and MP3 files. Cassette liners were also digitized at CTMD and are available as PDF files.
Arrangement
The Michael Alpert collection is organized in 9 series:
Series 1: Bronya Sakina recordings, 1982-1988
Series 2: Leon Schwartz recordings, 1979-1992
Series 3: German Goldenshteyn recordings, 1988-2006
Series 4: Ben Bazyler recordings, 1984-1996
Series 5: Soviet Jewish Folk Arts Program recordings, 1982-1983
Series 6: Eastern Europe field recordings, 1956-2007 (bulk: 1982-2007)
Series 7: North American field recordings, 1959-2008 (bulk: 1974-2008)
Series 8: Brave Old World and Michael Alpert's personal recordings, 1982-2003
Series 9: Miscellaneous recordings, performances, lectures, and interviews, 1979-2004
Digital surrogates are labeled with the original ID number assigned by Alpert and are arranged by this ID number in their archival information package (AIP). Born-digital materials are arranged by their Alpert ID number in their AIP and are described at the item level in their respective series. The following Alpert ID numbers are in each AIP:
afc2017048_dc001_aip_01: audio files for Alpert 001 through Alpert 584
afc2017048_dc001_aip_02: audio files for Alpert 585 through Alpert 1179
Digital surrogates of cassette liners are arranged by Alpert ID number in afc2017048_dc001_aip_01.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Alpert, Michael; Bazyler, Ben; Bern, Alan, 1955-; Birnboym, Marṭin; Bogdanski, Majer; Boyarin, Jonathan; Brody, Lauren; Brotman, Stuart; Burstein, Lillian Lux; Feldman, Walter; Flam, Gila, 1956-; Fogelson, Irina; Gajicki, Bora; Gendler, Arkady; Goldenshteyn, German; Gottesman, Itzik Nakhmen; Gran, Wiera; Hescheles, Jeremiah, 1910-; Jagoda, Flory; Kligman, Mark L., 1962-; Kochan, Alexis, 1953-; Kozłowski, Leopold, 1918-; Krakauer, David, 1956-; Kugelmass, Jack; Kytasty, Julian; Layman, Sandra; Leuchter, Janet; Loeffler, James Benjamin; Mayer, Lisa (Musician); Mazor, Yaakov; Moody, Richard (Musician); Netsky, Hankus; Offen, Sam, 1921-; Perlman, Itzhak, 1945-; Richmond, Ken; Roṭenberg, Yaʻaḳov, 1926-; Rubin, Joel, 1955-; Sakina, Bronya; Sapoznik, Henry; Schaechter-Gottesman, Beyle; Schlamme, Martha; Schwartz, Leon, 1901-1990; Seroussi, Edwin; Shaffir, M. M.; Sklamberg, Lorin; Skuse, David; Slobin, Mark; Spagnolo Acht, Francesco; Statman, Andy, 1950-; Steinlauf, Michael C.; Strauss, Deborah; Taub, Eda; Waletzky, Josh; Warschauer, Jeff
Organizations
Brave Old World (Musical group); Kapelye (Musical group); Paris to Kyiv (Musical group); Shashmaqam (Musical group); Strauss Warschauer Duo
Subjects
Folk musicians--New York (State)--New York--Interviews.; Folk songs, Yiddish--Europe, Eastern.; Folk songs, Yiddish--United States.; Jews, Romanian--New York (State)--New York--Interviews.; Jews, Soviet--New York (State)--New York--Interviews.; Jews, Ukrainian--New York (State)--New York--Interviews.; Klezmer music--Europe.; Klezmer music--United States.
Form/Genre
Field recordings.; Sound recordings.
Container List
- Series 1: Bronya Sakina recordings
  Conversations, interviews, and performances with Bronya Sakina (1910-1988), a Yiddish folk singer from Southern Ukraine. Sakina sang traditional, unaccompanied solo Yiddish folk songs. Included in this series are performances for the Ethnic Folk Arts Center, KlezKamp, Columbia-YIVO Summer Program, and the Soviet Jewish Folk Arts Program. Additional recordings of Bronya Sakina can be found in Series 5.
  - Bronya Sakina, 1982-1983, AFC 2017/048: SR0002; Personnel: Bronya Sakina.; Recording location: Jewish Community House (JCH), Bay Parkway, Bensonhurst, Brooklyn, NY.; Alpert 003; 1 sound cassette
  - Bronya Sakina, 1982-1983, AFC 2017/048: SR0003; Personnel: Bronya Sakina.; Recording location, Side A Jewish Community House (JCH), Bay Parkway, Bensonhurst, Brooklyn, NY. Recording location, Side B: Sakina's home in Brooklyn.; Alpert 004-005; 1 sound cassette
  - Korobov, Sakina, 1982-1984, AFC 2017/048: SR0004; Personnel: Side A: Leonid Korobov, Bronya Sakina. Personnel, Side B Bronya Sakina, Izzy Kuperman.; Recording location, Side A Queens? Recording location, Side B: Sakina's home in Brooklyn.; Alpert 006-007; 1 sound cassette
  - Bronya Sakina, JCH, July-August, 1982, AFC 2017/048: SR0005; Personnel, Side A: Bronya Sakina, Paula Teitelbaum, Carol Freeman, Gail Zaninovich. Personnel, Side B: Bronya Sakina.; Recording location: JCH Brooklyn?; Alpert 008-009; 1 sound cassette
  - Bronya Sakina, Alpert/Schlesinger Reels 1 and 2, September 27, 1987, AFC 2017/048: SR0006; Personnel: Bronya Sakina, Michael Alpert, Michael Schlesinger, Modrkhe Skurka.; Recording location: Sakina's home in Brooklyn.; Alpert 010-011; 1 sound cassette
  - Bronya Sakina, Alpert/Schlesinger Reels 1 and 2 (Copy), September 27, 1987, AFC 2017/048: SR0652; Personnel: Bronya Sakina, Michael Alpert, Michael Schlesinger, Modrkhe Skurka.; Recording location: Sakina's home in Brooklyn.; Alpert 010-011; 1 sound cassette
  - Bronya Sakina, Alpert/Schlesinger Reels 3 and 4, September 27, 1987, AFC 2017/048: SR0007; Personnel: Bronya Sakina, Michael Alpert, Michael Schlesinger, Modrkhe Skurka.; Recording location: Sakina's home in Brooklyn.; Alpert 012-013; 1 sound cassette
  - Bronya Sakina, Alpert/Schlesinger Reels 3 and 4 (Copy), September 27, 1987, AFC 2017/048: SR0653; Personnel: Bronya Sakina, Michael Alpert, Michael Schlesinger, Modrkhe Skurka.; Recording location: Sakina's home in Brooklyn.; Alpert 012-013; 1 sound cassette
  - Bronya Sakina-II, July 10, 1983, AFC 2017/048: SR0008; Personnel: Bronya Sakina, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 014-015; 1 sound cassette
  - Bronya Sakina, Alpert/Schlesinger Reels: end 4, reels 5 and 6 Side B, September 27, 1987, AFC 2017/048: SR0009; Personnel: Bronya Sakina, Michael Alpert, Michael Schlesinger, Modrkhe Skurka.; Recording location: Sakina's home in Brooklyn.; Alpert 016-017; 1 sound cassette
  - Bronya Sakina, Alpert/Schlesinger Reels: end 4, reels 5 and 6 Side B (Copy), September 27, 1987, AFC 2017/048: SR0654; Personnel: Bronya Sakina, Michael Alpert, Michael Schlesinger, Modrkhe Skurka.; Recording location: Sakina's home in Brooklyn.; Alpert 016-017; 1 sound cassette
  - Bronya Sakina-III; Phone call, 1983-1984, AFC 2017/048: SR0010; Personnel: Bronya Sakina, Michael Alpert, Hersch (last name unknown), Izzy Kuperman.; Recording location: Sakina's home in Brooklyn.; Alpert 018; 1 sound cassette
  - Bronya Sakina-I, December 13, 1985, AFC 2017/048: SR0011; Personnel: Bronya Sakina, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 019-020; 1 sound cassette
  - Bronya Sakina-II, December 13, 1985, AFC 2017/048: SR0012; Personnel: Bronya Sakina, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 021-022; 1 sound cassette
  - Bronya Sakina & Izzy Kuperman, December 11, 1984, AFC 2017/048: SR0013; Personnel: Bronya Sakina, Izzy Kuperman, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Sakina's home in Brooklyn.; Alpert 023-024; 1 sound cassette
  - Bronya Sakina & Izzy Kuperman, March 14, 1985, AFC 2017/048: SR0014; Personnel: Bronya Sakina, Izzy Kuperman, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: L-Room.; Alpert 025-026; 1 sound cassette
  - Bronya Sakina & Izzy Kuperman, March 14, 1985, AFC 2017/048: SR0015; Personnel: Bronya Sakina, Izzy Kuperman.; Recording location: L-Room.; Alpert 027; 1 sound cassette
  - Bronya Sakina, August 6, 1985, AFC 2017/048: SR0016; Personnel: Bronya Sakina, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Sakina's home in Brooklyn.; Alpert 028-029; 1 sound cassette
  - Bronya Sakina, March 18, 1984, AFC 2017/048: SR0017; Personnel: Bronya Sakina, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Ethnic Folk Arts Center.; Alpert 030-031; 1 sound cassette
  - Bronya Sakina, Mordkhe Skorka, 1985-1986, AFC 2017/048: SR0018; Personnel: Bronya Sakina, Mordkhe Skórka.; Alpert 032; 1 sound cassette
  - Bronya Sakina, KlezKamp, 1985, AFC 2017/048: SR0019; Personnel: Bronya Sakina.; Recording location: Klez-Kamp 1985.; Alpert 033; 1 sound cassette
  - Bronya Sakina, July 21, 1983, AFC 2017/048: SR0020; Personnel: Bronya Sakina, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Columbia-YIVO Summer Program.; Alpert 034-035; 1 sound cassette
  - Bronya Sakina, 1987, AFC 2017/048: SR0021; Personnel: Bronya Sakina, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 036-037; 1 sound cassette
  - Bronya Sakina, Mordkhe Skurka-I, 1987, AFC 2017/048: SR0022; Personnel: Bronya Sakina, Michael Alpert, Mordkhe Skurka.; Alpert 038-039; 1 sound cassette
  - Bronya Sakina, Aires Navideños, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0023; Personnel: Bronya Sakina, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 040-041; 1 sound cassette
  - Bronya Sakina, Mordkhe Skurka, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0024; Personnel: Bronya Sakina, Mordkhe Skurka.; Alpert 042; 1 sound cassette
  - Bronya Sakina- II, 1987, AFC 2017/048: SR0025; Personnel: Bronya Sakina.; Alpert 043; 1 sound cassette
  - Bronya Sakina, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0026; Personnel: Bronya Sakina.; Alpert 044-045; 1 sound cassette
  - Bronya Sakina, Workshop BRJCC, June 26, 1988, AFC 2017/048: SR0027; Personnel: Bronya Sakina.; Recording location: Berkeley-Richmond Jewish Community Center, Berkeley, CA.; Alpert 046-047; 1 sound cassette
  - Bronya Sakina, YIVO Institute, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0138; Personnel: Bronya Sakina.; Recording location: YIVO Institute for Jewish Research.; Alpert 239; 1 sound cassette
  - Digital surrogates of recordings in Series 1, 1982-1988, afc2017048_dc001; Digital copies of audio are available as both WAV and MP3 files. PDF files depicting the outside of each audio carrier are also available for many of the recordings.; 46 WAV, 46 MP3, 27 PDF
- Series 2: Leon Schwartz recordings
  Conversations, interviews, lessons, and performances with Leon Schwartz (1901-1989), a klezmer violinist from the Bukovina region of Ukraine. Schwartz immigrated to the United States in 1921. Included in this series are performances for the Ethnic Folk Arts Center, Jewish Ethnic Music Festival, KlezKamp, YIVO Institute, Postcrypt Coffeehouse, Rodeph Sholom School, Jewish Museum, and recordings for his published album and the Soviet Jewish Folk Arts Program. Life in a Different World. Also included are Michael Alpert's lessons with Schwartz and recordings of Schwartz playing with his brother, Burekh Schwartz.
  - Leon Schwartz, Zevulun Avshalomov, April 1981, AFC 2017/048: SR0028; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Zevulun Avshalomov, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Jewish Ethnic Music Festival.; Alpert 048-049; 1 sound cassette
  - Burekh Schwartz (excerpts), November 1986, AFC 2017/048: SR0029; Personnel: Burekh Schwartz, Leon Schwartz, Michael Alpert (sekund).; Alpert 050-051; 1 sound cassette
  - Burekh Comparison, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0030; Personnel: Burekh Schwartz, Leon Schwartz.; Alpert 052; 1 sound cassette
  - Burekh Schwartz, Leon Schwartz Comparison Tape I, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0031; Personnel: Burekh Schwartz, Leon Schwartz.; Alpert 053-054; 1 sound cassette
  - Burekh Schwartz, Leon Schwartz Comparison Tape II, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0032; Personnel: Burekh Schwartz, Leon Schwartz.; Alpert 055-056; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz I, October 18, 1983, AFC 2017/048: SR0033; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 057-058; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz II, November 1, 1984, AFC 2017/048: SR0034; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Schwartz's home.; Alpert 059-060; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz III, November 1, 1984, AFC 2017/048: SR0035; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Schwartz's home.; Alpert 061-062; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz IV, 1984-1985, AFC 2017/048: SR0036; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 063-064; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz V, January 24, 1985, AFC 2017/048: SR0037; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 065-066; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz VI, ca. 1985, AFC 2017/048: SR0038; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 067-068; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz VII, July 26, 1985, AFC 2017/048: SR0039; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Schwartz's home.; Alpert 069-070; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz, March 18, 1984, AFC 2017/048: SR0040; Personnel: Leon Schwartz.; Recording location: Ethnic Folk Arts Center.; Alpert 071; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz, 1985-1986, AFC 2017/048: SR0041; Personnel: Leon Schwartz.; Recording location: YIVO Institute.; Alpert 072; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz, October 11, 1985, AFC 2017/048: SR0042; Personnel: Leon Schwartz.; Alpert 073-074; 1 sound cassette
  - Helen Salomon, Leon Schwartz, 1979-1985, AFC 2017/048: SR0043; Personnel: Helen Salomon; Leon Schwartz, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 075-076; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz, January 10, 1986, AFC 2017/048: SR0044; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 077-078; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz-I, January 14, 1986, AFC 2017/048: SR0045; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 079-080; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz-II, Charlotte Schwartz-I, January 14, 1986, AFC 2017/048: SR0046; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Charlotte Schwartz, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 081-082; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz-II, 1986, AFC 2017/048: SR0047; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 083-084; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz, Gottesmans, parts 1A and 1B, 1986, AFC 2017/048: SR0048; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Bella Gottesman, Yona Gottesman, Itzik Gottesman, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 085-086; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz, Itzik Gottesman, parts 1 and III, February 4-17, 1986, AFC 2017/048: SR0049; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Itzik Gottesman, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 087-088; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz, Itzik Gottesman, part II, February 17, 1986, AFC 2017/048: SR0050; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Itzik Gottesman, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Leon's kitchen and living room.; Alpert 089-090; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz, Itzik Gottesman, part III, February 17, 1986, AFC 2017/048: SR0051; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Itzik Gottesman, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Leon's living room.; Alpert 091; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz, Itzik Gottesman, excerpts, February 17, 1986, AFC 2017/048: SR0052; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Itzik Gottesman, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Leon's living room.; Alpert 092-093; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz (excerpts), March 6, 1986, AFC 2017/048: SR0053; Personnel: Leon Schwartz.; Alpert 094-095; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz, Jerry Kisslinger, Rebecca Miller, Michael Alpert, April, 1986, AFC 2017/048: SR0054; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Jerry Kisslinger, Rebecca Miller, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 096-097; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz, Yugntruf concert, April 20, 1986, AFC 2017/048: SR0055; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Jerry Kisslinger, Rebecca Miller, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 098-099; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz I, July 14, 1986, AFC 2017/048: SR0056; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 100-101; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz II, July 14, 1986, AFC 2017/048: SR0057; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 102; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz - A Jumpin' Nite, August 27, 1986, AFC 2017/048: SR0058; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 103-104; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz - A Jumpin' Nite II, August 27, 1986, AFC 2017/048: SR0059; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 105; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz - A Jumpin' Nite III, August 27, 1986, AFC 2017/048: SR0060; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 106; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz I, November 3, 1986, AFC 2017/048: SR0061; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 107-108; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz II, November 3, 1986, AFC 2017/048: SR0062; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 109; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz at Bashevis Birthday Party, November 13, 1986, AFC 2017/048: SR0063; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Michael Alpert, Isaac Bashevis, Bashevis Family.; Recording location: 104th & West End Ave, NYC.; Alpert 110-111; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz, January 8, 1987, AFC 2017/048: SR0064; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 112-113; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz, Sandra Layman- I, January 18, 1987, AFC 2017/048: SR0065; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Sandra Layman, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Sunnyside, Queens, NY.; Alpert 114-115; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz, Sandra Layman-II; Leon Schwartz, Horty and Larry, January 18, 1987, AFC 2017/048: SR0066; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Sandra Layman, Michael Alpert; Leon Schwartz, Horty and Larry.; Recording location: Sunnyside, Queens, NY; unknown.; Alpert 116-117; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz, David Skuse, Mimi Koyama- I, February 22, 1987, AFC 2017/048: SR0067; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, David Skuse, Mimi Koyama, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 118-119; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz, David Skuse, Mimi Koyama- II, February 22, 1987, AFC 2017/048: SR0068; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, David Skuse, Mimi Koyama, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 120; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz, Jerry Kisslinger- I, March 24, 1987, AFC 2017/048: SR0069; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Jerry Kisslinger, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 121-122; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz, Jerry Kisslinger- II; Leon Schwartz-II, March 24, April 8, 1987, AFC 2017/048: SR0070; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Jerry Kisslinger, Michael Alpert; Leon Schwartz, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 123-124; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz-III, April 8, 1987, AFC 2017/048: SR0071; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 125-126; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz excerpts, March 24, April 8, 1987, AFC 2017/048: SR0072; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 127-128; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz, Paule Epstein, May 7, 1987, AFC 2017/048: SR0073; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Paule Epstein, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 129-130; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz- I, June 23, 1987, AFC 2017/048: SR0074; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Schwartz's home.; Alpert 131-132; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz- I (Copy), June 23, 1987, AFC 2017/048: SR0655; Alpert 131-132; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz- II, June 23, 1987, AFC 2017/048: SR0075; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Schwartz's home.; Alpert 133; 1 sound cassette
  - CM Schwartz, June 30, 1987, AFC 2017/048: SR0076; Personnel: CM Schwartz.; Recording location: Sheraton Center.; Alpert 134-135; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz- Postcrypt Coffeehouse, October 24, 1987, AFC 2017/048: SR0077; Personnel: Leon Schwartz.; Recording location: Postcrypt Coffeehouse.; Alpert 136-137; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz- Rodeph Sholom School, January 20, 1988, AFC 2017/048: SR0078; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Rodeph Sholom Day School.; Alpert 138-139; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz, Jerry Kisslinger, Kurt Bjorling- I, February 4, 1988, AFC 2017/048: SR0079; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Jerry Kisslinger, Kurt Bjorling, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 140-141; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz, Jerry Kisslinger, Kurt Bjorling- II, February 4, March 6, 1988, AFC 2017/048: SR0080; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Jerry Kisslinger, Kurt Bjorling, Michael Alpert; Leon Schwartz, Jerry Kisslinger, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 142-143; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz, Jerry Kisslinger- II, March 6, 1988, AFC 2017/048: SR0081; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Jerry Kisslinger, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 144-145; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz, Kapelye- I, March 13, 1988, AFC 2017/048: SR0082; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Jerry Kisslinger, Michael Alpert, Kapelye.; Recording location: Jewish Museum.; Alpert 146-147; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz, Kapelye-II, March 13, 1988, AFC 2017/048: SR0083; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Jerry Kisslinger, Michael Alpert, Kapelye.; Recording location: Jewish Museum.; Alpert 148; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz- KlezKamp, December 27, 1988, AFC 2017/048: SR0084; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Michael Alpert, Koram, Stuart Brotman, Daniel.; Recording location: KlezKamp.; Alpert 149-150; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz, February 15, 1989, AFC 2017/048: SR0085; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Charlotte Schwartz, Robbie Newman, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Leon and Charlotte Schwartz's home; Alpert 151-152; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz-Telephone, May 10, 1989, AFC 2017/048: SR0086; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Telephone conversation.; Alpert 153-154; 1 sound cassette
  - Leon Schwartz- I, January 21, 1990, AFC 2017/048: SR0087; Personnel: Leon Schwartz, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Leon and Charlotte Schwartz's home.; Alpert 155-156; 1 sound cassette